China has risen up, and we can't avoid any questions or doubts.
What should they know about the history of China?
What conflicts will emerge as time moves on?
I hope to awake all the Chinese people about our own system.
Is it better to unify Taiwan sooner or later?
Students have endless tutoring sessions after school
for better grades. How do you interpret this?
China successfully fought the intruders and became self-sufficient.
But we still face unfair criticisms.
What is the root cause of our inability to tell the stories of China?
Perhaps we have so much to tell and don't know where to begin.
At first, it was the lack of confidence.
Now, we have the confidence but we realize that
just like how trademarks and patents can be registered,
some words have already been registered.
Such as "democracy", "rule of law", and "human rights".
It seems that our "democracy", "rule of law"
and "human rights" don't match their definitions.
That's so strange.
How could we use these terms equally?
Having our right of speech is important.
Since the 20th century, especially in the first half of it,
China had no say internationally.
At that time, China had no choice but to passively accept things.
Now, we are able to compete with these concepts
but we find ourselves at a disadvantage.
Especially for words like "democracy".
The key question is whether we have the right
to enrich the definition of "democracy".
China is on a democratic path.
What we have is democracy.
We won't stop using the word "democracy" because they say it's not.
In fact, many information channels, such as Ministry of
Foreign Affairs, have always been explaining.
We not only need the official channels, but also the folk channels.
My niece went to a university in Taiwan.
She discussed with a philosophy professor
to compare Taiwan and the mainland.
Finally, the professor played what he
thought would be a "trump card".
"You don't have democracy. You don't have elections."
"The mainland might be better in many ways,
but it doesn't have elections."
Every time they want you to shut your mouth.
And my niece replied calmly,
"Yes, you have elections.
But can you elect a president like Xi Jinping?"
Good companies makes good products.
The best companies make the standards.
So, if you can establish new and reasonable standards,
your will hold your ground.
I think it's time to reshape the standards
for values and political voices.
The Communist Party of China [CCP] has an advantage.
CCP has the courage to reform instead of fearing it.
It is also strong in constructing China's own language.
The CPC is consciously making reforms.
In the past few years, several big
programs were very successful.
Especially the CPC in Dialogue with World
Political Parties High-Level Meeting.
When the CPC increase exchange with other parties in
the world, it will enhance their understanding about us.
Is China a true lover of peace, or a country
like some western media reported?
I believe everyone in the world can see with their own eyes.
When we talk about China to other countries,
we are not saying "Only what I say is right".
We hope to initiate discussions
and hear each other's opinions.
And I can tell you that if you follow your logic,
you can't explain the problems you will face.
That's also what we expect to hear from Professor Zhang.
In this episode, we mainly talk about making China's voice heard.
Yes, China's voice.
Professor Zhang, you have attended some
major international debates with western scholars.
The debates help both sides introspect.
Do domestic scholars challenge you as well?
Domestically, we don't have such an atmosphere.
People with different opinions are unwilling to debate each other.
(An economist) Chen Ping always says that
he can't find someone to debate with
although he keeps posting online.
We tried to invite people who disagree with you
or who want to challenge you in the live audience.
They are especially welcome.
Now, people who challenge us are usually not influential scholars.
Mainly, the Internet offers them channels to to heard.
There are groups working behind them
but the composition and background of
the groups are unclear. Not just researchers.
- Hello everyone, it's time for the show.
- Okay, let's go.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Hello everyone, welcome to China Now.
We are here learn about China and understand China!
Standing next to me is our keynote speaker,
Professor Zhang Weiwei, Director of the
China Institute of Fudan University. Welcome!
There are many people in the audience
today, including our pre-production panel.
We look forward to your dialogue with Professor Zhang.
We will begin with the keynote speech by Professor Zhang.
Now, I will give the stage to Professor Zhang. Please.
Recently, you may have notice lots of good news about high-speed rail.
Not long ago, the State Council passed the plan of
the "eight vertical and eight horizontal" network.
Our high-speed rail mileage now accounts for two-thirds of the world’s.
We will make more progress from there.
According to the latest plan, the mileage of China's high-
speed rail will reach 38,000 kilometers by 2025.
I am proud of the great achievements
of China's high-speed rail.
Besides, it brings back some of my memories.
I’m going to share them with you.
Eight years ago, in 2011, I published the book
"China Shock: the Rise of a Civilized Country".
This book was influential and I received
many invitations to give speeches.
That year in August, I was invited to
one institute in Shanghai.
A media professional asked me a rather pointed question.
"Haven't you heard about the 7.23 high-speed
train accident that just happened?"
He mocked me, "Is this another a China shock?"
This was his question.
I said that the accident was undoubtedly a tragedy.
"We need to investigate the accident and do everything we should."
I also explained to him that it was in fact the collision
of two electric multiple-unit [EMU] trains,
which are different from high-speed trains.
EMU trains has the speed limit of 250 km/h.
I said frankly, "You have to compare or measure
the safety levels of the trains based on a specific frame of reference".
China is a country of 1.4 billion people.
There are more than 3 billion
passenger trips during the Spring Festival.
I am afraid that is more than the number of
train passengers for ten years in Germany.
I also learned that by August 2011,
our EMU and high-speed trains had been running
safely all across our country for five years.
That must be one of the best records in the world.
I proposed an analogy that if our EMU and
high-speed trains were graduate students,
trains in the US and the UK would be secondary school students,
and trains in India would be kindergartens.
Frankly speaking, graduate students may also make mistakes,
and middle school students may point out these mistakes,
but the gap between middle school and
graduate school is not small.
If you go to India and travel by train,
which I have in many trips,
you can watch trains entering Mumbai every morning.
Many people cling to the tops and the doors of the trains.
Just like the old movie "Railway Guerrilla",
which many of you might not have watched.
So many accidents happen every day.
Fatalities caused by trains are counted in thousands in India.
If you deny the great contribution that our railway
workers have made to China's modernization
because of one accident,
that is unwise and irrational in my view.
We now even built high speed rails in
the Yunnan-Guizhou Plateau
despite its challenging geological conditions.
To build high-speed rail in provinces like Guizhou or Sichuan
might be even more difficult than building it across the USA.
We must consider all these factors and differences
to make an objective and rational comparison.
One problem behind his question is that
even if we did so well in developing high-speed rail,
some people may twist or reverse the story
if we don't do well telling the story.
Our "positive assets" will turn into "negative assets".
You may remember that at that time,
when the Internet was emerging,
so many people were shaming China online
and seemed to be dominant.
"The government is bad."
"The state-owned enterprises are bad."
"So the high-speed rail built by the
state-owned enterprises are also bad."
Some mainstream media were also
carried away by the opinions on the Internet.
I have a lot to say on this issue.
I have been to the Soviet Union before its dissolution.
And Yugoslavia before it broke up.
I understand how the dissolution happened through two phases.
In the first phase, the intellectual elites,
like university professors and media editors
were sold on the Western narratives.
They began to believe that as long as they adopted
the Western political and economic models,
all the problems facing their country could be solved.
Then, in the second phase, the political elites,
like members of the Politburo, the standing committee,
and even in the general secretary,
were also sold on Western narratives.
Then, the economy collapsed and the country dissolved.
After that, all their wealth was looted by the West.
These are profound lessons.
The most persuasive example is Gorbachev, who was
completely sold on Western narratives.
This led to the collapse of the Soviet Union.
Today, when you meet a Russian who has a little sense of history,
he will tell you that Russia has experienced three catastrophes.
The first catastrophe was the Mongol invasion in the 14th century.
The second one was the Nazi German invasion during
World War II.
The third one was the collapse of the Soviet Union.
Gorbachev was an interesting person.
He even participated in the 1996 presidential campaign.
The result was conceivable.
His approval rating was less than 1%.
The Russian people abandoned him.
Looking back to 2011, I personally think that,
many of the Chinese intellectual elites were
so sold on the Western narratives.
Even today, some still are.
But I think more and more people are see through the
western narratives now, especially the younger generations.
Even the good story of our successful
high-speed rail development could be twisted.
You may remember some were saying, "High-speed trains, please wait for The People".
"High-speed trains, wait for your conscience"
and so on.
This tells us the importance of narrative.
We must make our stories clear in our ’s own words.
So China's rise will be one that's smooth and inspiring.
Otherwise, even though we have achieved a lot,
we might end up in a collapse,
making all our efforts in vain.
China's rise has come to a stage
that our future generations would blame us
if we still buy into the shallow Western narratives.
They would say, "How could you lose when you had such a good hand?"
In fact, for so many years, we have been solely
devoted to [infrastructure] construction,
to [economic] development,
and to improving people's livelihood.
The Chinese people are ready to follow good advice.
If you do it well, we are eager to learn how you do it.
But the West is different. We say "The wind never spares
the tree that wishes to remain in peace."
Its massive ideologization and politicization cause
all kinds of silly questions to be thrown upon the Chinese people.
Ordinary westerners would ask you questions like:
Why does Chines have horrible human rights?
Why can't Tibet be independent?
What's the matter if Taiwan becomes a country?
You don't really mind answering such questions once or twice.
But when you study abroad or stay for a long time, you
will probably have to answer hundreds of them.
China has risen up, I don't think we can
avoid any questions any more.
We must be able to respond to all the doubts.
We should be able to explain China's stories in our own words.
In this new era of China's rise, we face the defamation of China.
Not only from the West, but also from within.
Some intellectuals and media professionals lack confidence.
They follow the West to attack our
country and our system.
However, I see the influence of this group of people has been declining.
Someone say that the Chinese Communist Party
has developed its own narrative.
I agree.
Narratives are important.
They are like "Monkey King's magical staff
which maintains the stability in the East Sea".
They build consensus among people.
But official narratives are not enough. Why?
Because on the one hand, the world is still led by Western narratives.
On the other hand, our society is increasingly open with new media.
Official narratives alone are not enough to respond to defamation.
Therefore, I urge that we internationalize Chinese narratives on academic and individual levels.
In a sense, this will make up for shortcomings in
our current narrative construction.
For example, the West always talk about China's human rights issues,
Some of our officials and scholars would explain,
“China is still a developing country.
We are in a lower stage than your country."
"So our human rights fall short of your standards”.
I personally think that is a weak narrative.
They are still talking in the Western narrative system.
That is, you give up your own right of
speech to the West with both hands
and let the West judge your human rights.
Someone asked me: “How would you answer this question?"
I said it's not difficult to answer.
If you view human rights from the perspective of Chinese people,
or view it under the UN’s standards on human rights,
I must say that the Iraq War is the worst
violation of human rights in the 21st century so far.
More than 100,000 civilians died.
Millions were displaced or homeless.
You can tell the Americans frankly that
if you can’t explain this serious violation
to people in Iraq, in China, and the rest of the world,
you don't have the right to talk about human rights with us.
I think this is a stronger Chinese narrative.
Everyone knows that over the years,
the West describes mainstream political
paradigms as "Democracy" or "Autocracy".
And "Democracy" or "Autocracy" are defined by Western countries.
Democracy can only be adopting the multi-
party system and universal suffrage.
This is their so-called “universal value”.
Many West scholars and the media, in my words,
are "taking the lazy man's way".
They will ask you: "When will you reform your political system?"
"Why hasn't China reformed its political system?"
If you do not move closer to the Western model,
you don't meet their standards
and your society will never be seen as
a mainstream or a civilized one.
The paradigm of dividing countries into "democracies" or "autocracies"
has long been an ideological instrument for the West
to spark color revolutions and to subvert non-Western governments.
Such a narrative can still sell well to some
as they have caused regime changes in quite a few countries.
However, we see that the Arab Spring turned into the Arab Winter,
as the West itself faces more problems,
many Westerners are starting to see more
problems in the Western political model.
Some Westerners began to reflect on their model.
At the end of 2008, I visited India and gave a speech.
In that November, some of you may remember,
a serious large-scale terrorist attack happened in Mumbai.
It took India's elite anti-terrorist forces nine hours to
arrive at where the attack happened.
During my stay, there was an uproar across Indian media.
I happened to be giving a talk on the
China Model at the University of Delhi.
In the Q&A section, one person asked
this question in a quite friendly manner.
He asked: "How would China respond to such a terrorist attack?"
I answered that China had not had a terrorist attack of such scale.
The Urumqi 7.5 Incident in Xinjiang may be
but it happened in 2009.
I said in China's response to the 2008
Wenchuan earthquake, magnitude 8,
The epicenter was in Sichuan, a mountainous province in central China,
far away from our economic and financial centers.
But our army was mobilized within 20 minutes.
Our leaders began to fly to the disaster area in two hours.
Our medical teams covered all affected towns
in three days which were over 1000 in number
and directly helped more than 20
million affected people.
I can still remember how the Indian scholar looked.
Obviously, he was unconvinced.
So he asked another question.
He asked whether I wanted to prove that
autocracy is more efficient than democracy.
I said this statement was not kind or fair.
Frankly, we shouldn't be talking about the
efficiency of autocracy and democracy,
but the efficiency of good governance and bad governance.
This is an important conclusion from my research.
I call it the overthrow of the paradigm.
I also added that good governance can be a Western system
or a non-Western system.
This is an important view.
China is a typical example.
Our system has its own problems.
But as a whole, it has done a better job than most of the world.
More importantly, bad governance can also be a Western system.
I can count a hundred examples.
From the worst systems like Iraq, Afghanistan, Haiti, Liberia, etc.
to the bankrupt governments in developed countries like Greece and Iceland.
They didn't achieve good governance.
I remember that the audience was silent
after hearing my answer.
The moderator of the meeting said "It seems that we
Indians are also reflecting on our system."
I believe that along with the rise of China,
the paradigm of Chinese narratives will be accepted
by more countries, scholars, and people.
The reason behind this is that our narrative
"seeks truth from the facts" and shows the truth.
A lot more can be shared about this.
But today I will end my speech for now. Thank you everyone.
Thank you, Professor Zhang. Please have a seat.
You said we need to make China's stories clear
to ourselves and the international community.
So, where should we start?
The scale of China's rise is large.
Thousands of projects in the “Belt and Road” Initiative.
I have discussed Chinese narrative with
some leaders of state-owned enterprises.
I said building the infrastructure abroad isn't enough.
You need to talk on TV stations and the Internet.
You can tell the audience why we're building this
and what kind of benefits it will bring to the people.
Talk about specific problems.
Yes, everyone can be an envoy,
a speaker, and a promoter.
Next, comments from the panel.
In recent years, Xi Jinping's book "The Governance of China"
has been translated into many languages.
It's a globally well-received book.
People's interest in China's governance
also shows that Western democratic theories have flaws.
Even if they don't admit it now,
there will be someone who eventually points it out.
I don't think they will admit it.
No. And I feel that it's time someone should point it out.
A responsible country should tell the truth.
However, some international rules are not
effectively binding the hegemonic governments.
They were able to get around the UN
Security Council and start the war.
They also managed to bypass the opposition from the American people.
In the end, most incredibly, Bush Jr. said
that no evidence of such weapons was found,
And he could get away with that. It seems
that American democracy did not follow up on it.
I honestly don't understand why.
So, at the root of the problem, the true definition
of democracy should be open-ended,
not exclusively written by western scholars.
We all have the right to enrich and improve it.
The so-called "universal value", or whatever value, came pre-defined.
The word “universal” suggests the value applies to the
universe/world and hence occupies the highest ground .
When the latecomers try to renew this definition, they
are at a largely disadvantaged position.
Like I said earlier, our narrative must be based on
realities, and be able to make ourselves clear.
Sometimes, we need more than two narratives in one conversation.
We need some other narratives to serve as foundations
and bridges between them, for a good communication.
When we feel we are unable to tell the stories of China,
it's because we don't known enough about China.
Although we all live in China,
what do we know about our history
and our complicated social composition?
What kind of contradictions will emerge
as the time changes? How do we resolve them?
Many of us don't have the answers.
I hope "China Now" can clear our misunderstandings
of China's political system.
Many would think politics is dangerous and avoid talking about it.
Or “I can't explain it.”
But I think the younger generations are ready.
The audience of China Now has all come
with their observations and questions.
Now, it’s time for their pointed questions.
Please raise your hand if you have a question.
Yes, please. Welcome.
Hello, Professor Zhang and Madam Moderator.
I'm a government employee.
I'm very interested in Taiwan.
I would like to hear Professor Zhang's opinion on the
our country's reunification.
Is it better to do it sooner or later?
You're very straightforward.
Is it better to have a peaceful reunification or more feasible to have a non-peaceful one?
Different views can be discussed and debated.
We are not at all afraid of competition.
China, be confident.
China Now with Zhang Weiwei.
I'm very interested in Taiwan.
I would like to hear Professor Zhang's opinion on the
our country's reunification.
Is it better to do it sooner or later?
Is it better to have a peaceful reunification or more feasible to have a non-peaceful one?
If you read President Xi’s speech at the
fortieth anniversary of publishing
“The Message to Compatriots in Taiwan”,
There was a well-said comment:
"The Taiwan issue stemmed from China’s past weakness and poverty"
"and will end in our nation's great rejuvenation."
It's not difficult to interpret this statement.
If we look at our recently launched Taiwan policies,
Professor Zhang likes to view China's problems through global comparison.
The Koreans are envious of our free travels across the Taiwan Strait.
Over 6 million people fly across the strait a year now.
The Koreans say, "You are not divided."
General Secretary Xi Jinping said in 2014:
"Our pursuit is not only the unity in form, but also
the harmony of the people."
From this perspective, unity in form is not the problem to be worried about.
This is the ultimate unification
which achieves spiritual harmony and integrated development.
Let us briefly review the recent Taiwan policies.
The "31 Measures” launched on February 28, 2018
[to attract talent and investment]
and the application policy in September 2018 on
residence permit for Taiwan residents.
This question can be answered by a few idioms,
“The melon will fall from the stem when it is ripe”
and “The channel will be formed hen the river arrives”.
I believe many people have the same concern as well.
All right, let's go on to the next question.
Yes, please.
Hello Madam Moderator and Professor Zhang.
I am a post-90s student.
Alipay has changed the payment habits of our generation,
and e-commerce has changed our shopping habits.
As far as I know, these originated from Western countries.
What do you think about such changes. Thank you.
I will take Alipay for example.
Why can Alipay grow so fast in China?
Alipay and WeChat Pay,
are not feasible in the United States.
One important reason is the resistance from large interest groups.
Especially banks and credit card companies.
They make money easily and don’t want to be impeded.
But in China, one of Xi Jinping's economic thoughts
is the supply-side structural reform.
Our society has a huge demand for it,
so the government supports its development.
In a sense, it suppresses the growth of
our domestic banks and credit card companies.
Despite all the voices of opposition,
we started developing online payment.
We may have not expected that online payment led to a revolution.
There seem to be important political factors behind
the success of our Internet economy.
We have a political power that represents people's overall interests
and can overcome the obstacles from
vested interest.
We develop it and then solve emerging problems.
We try to balance with the interests of the banks and
credit card companies, and come to a solution.
Many of our inspirations come from the West and their good practices,
but we implement them the Chinese way.
When I was in Taiwan ten years ago,
Qinglin likes to talk about Taiwan because he worked as a journalist there.
Yes. They started talking about mobile payment and
non-monetary transactions ten years ago.
We thought that was very advanced.
But when Alipay and WeChat Pay have become popular
in the mainland, Taiwan still didn't implement mobile payment.
Why? Because most of the banks in Taiwan are privately owned.
The Fubon bank belongs to the Cai family of Cai,
and the First Commercial Bank belongs to Ma and Lin.
There is no third party who has the financial power
to break down the barriers between them.
Now, Taiwan has mobile payments
because Alipay and WeChat are paying the costs for this service.
They are subsidizing the small benefits of the private banks.
That’s why online payment was first implemented in the mainland
although Taiwan started talking about it first.
Okay, now any questions from this side of the audience?
Yes, please.
Hello, Professor Zhang.
I'm a student and I have a question about education.
Education is a country's soft power.
It has been very important over the forty
years since Reform and Opening-up.
[The education system has been significantly reformed]
But now, students face endless homework
and tutoring sessions to have good grades.
Many good teachers have to “teach to the test” and give lots of homework.
Some approve of them doing so while others don't.
I’d like to know what Professor Zhang thinks about this.
I'd also like to know whether this education model will
improve the quality of our population
or it's just "pulling up seedlings to help them grow".
How do Western countries do differently?
We have a lot to say when it comes to education.
The Western education systems in general,
especially in elementary schools,
is too easy from our perspective.
The students don't even have to
memorize the multiplication table.
This is not acceptable by the Chinese standards.
But Chinese education is criticized for being too strict
and giving students too much work.
We didn’t have so much pressure when we were in school.
Our generation was raised like the "free range lamb".
Our parents were too busy to take care of
so many children in the family.
Now, parents only have one child
and all the children have to cross one footlog bridge [gaokao standardized test].
I think the fundamental solution is a balance between
the Chinese and Western models.
We must be less strict, and they must work harder.
But be careful not to lose our advantages.
We gain solid knowledge from K12 education
and this is rare in the world.
I agree.
But knowledge goes beyond what we learn at school.
The kids need more time to play.
Sports, games, or anything,
they build team spirits,
and learn to deal with failure.
These are all important qualities.
I agree that we should reduce school workloads.
However, under the existing circumstances
if the Ministry of Education urges schools to reduce workloads,
all kinds of tutoring and training will
immediately dominate the market.
Because parents would always want their
children to spend more time studying.
China's rapid growth is not possible without
the educated "constructors" of the country.
Not only infrastructure construction, all
contributors to the country are constructing the country.
They've laid a very solid foundation for
China's rapid development.
And this is achieved through education.
As a parent, I also feel that children have too much work.
But just as Prof. Zhang said,
students still have to take exams even if we want to give them less work.
They still face the competition to enter better schools.
So, where should we start?
How can we relax the system to an appropriate extend?
Schools should also stop comparing the
number of graduates into good schools.
It’s boring.
If you study the Number One students in the gaokao exam of all provinces,
you can easily find that many of them didn't achieve high later in life.
What really matters, I think, is originality and creativity.
I worked as the translator for Deng Xiaoping
and Hu Yaobang in the mid-1980s.
They didn’t have high degrees.
But they are intelligent.
Getting into a college is not the only way to success.
Jack Ma is also one of the smartest people in the world.
"All roads lead to Rome."
I want to tell parents that university is not their only choice.
I remember seeing some jokes on the Internet
about how we should change our mindset.
It says, "How do you pay if one option is 0.27 yuan/item,
and the other is 0.35 yuan/item?"
The kid answers: "I pay with Alipay."
This is not about the kid being funny.
The kid is thinking out of the box.
I'd like to add that
I think now we need to be supportive of students
having preferences for some subjects.
When a child has an idea or a hobby,
give them the freedom to pursue it.
They don't need to be good at everything.
If they spend time on the things the love,
they might have already become the best in the world.
Chinese people are fairly well-off today
The parents all have properties now.
This might be the first generation of students in Chinese
history who don’t have to study for a living.
So, if the child loves something,
give them the freedom to pursue it.
They will devote themselves to it.
And they might do something amazing.
When we talk about education, I also feeling like saying more as well.
We all can relate to this topic.
We should have an episode on education some time.
Anyways, I just wanted to say that
there are still many students from poor families.
It might be difficult for them to receive "quality-oriented"
or "creativity-oriented" education.
I think ideally, I'm just thinking out loud,
we support quality-oriented education
but still give some children the opportunity to focus on exams.
They may not be able to afford creativity-oriented
or personality-discovering programs,
but they are good at exams from the education they receive
and this is their way to the future.
China, is a really big topic.
There're already so many aspects of education.
We must have a well-rounded understanding of China as well.
Different views can be discussed and debated.
We are not at all afraid of competition.
China, be confident.
China Now with Zhang Weiwei
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Yes, the girl in blue. Welcome.
Hello, Professor Zhang. I am a Kazakh student from Xinjiang.
I am now in my thrid year in a university in Nanjing.
- Did you make the trip just for our show?
- Yes, I did.
Thank you for coming.
Before asking my question, I would like to
share some of my opinions about Xinjiang.
First of all, despite a series of problems that happened in Xinjiang,
Xinjiang's economic and social environment has prospered
and the people are able to live and work in peace.
Over the past few years, we have been in the same boat striving for this
and it is truly... Peace, stability, and prosperity,
they are at the cost of the blood and tears of many.
Even though Xinjiang may not be as prosperous as
the costal or southern provinces,
Xinjiang has been doing well.
In terms of GDP and many other things, Xingjiang isn't among the lowest ranking regions.
It didn't fall behind.
Myself, from an ethnic minority, I identify with the Chinese culture.
I belong to the Chinese cultural sphere.
I speak Mandarin, and I use chopsticks.
You speak very well.
We were discussing the dominance of Western narratives.
This is a really serious issue.
And I feel a little ... aggrieved.
And, I think, Xinjiang’s development, I think it's China's miracle.
It’s ... It's an embodiment of China's growth.
Xinjiang is doing better and better.
And the people of all ethnic groups are united.
There's no "we and they".
My question is, what’s your opinion on
Xinjiang's current development?
And what do you think about the
misunderstandings and biases against Xinjiang?
- Great question.
- Please sit down.
I have visited Xinjiang this year.
Xinjiang is always a good place to visit.
Xinjiang’s doing very well economically.
I have a few things to say.
One is that after the Urumqi 7.5 Incident,
after such a serious terrorist incident,
we started to take special measures to counter terrorism.
I think that is completely understandable.
It should be understandable in any country.
Another thing is that, Kazakhs or Uyghurs
or any other ethnic minorities in Xinjiang,
their cultures are highly open overall.
We often say that ethnic minorities
are good at singing and dancing.
The girls are dressed colorfully and good at singing and dancing.
The data I have shows that, by August 2018,
Xinjiang received more than 100 million tourists,
the largest number in its history.
This is an amazing achievement showing that Xinjiang is very safe now.
You can go to anywhere you like.
In September 2018, our thinktank delegation visited Europe,
another delegation asked about Xinjiang.
I said that the Uyghurs still speak their own
language and use their own script today.
This is our respect for the rights of ethnic minorities.
Even though the members of our delegation are all Han people,
all of us can sing Uighur songs.
So, strictly speaking, we can teach them a lesson and enlighten them.
Thank you, Professor Zhang.
Our friends in the audience had their own concerns
and asked different questions.
But I think we will be able to put all these pieces together,
and have a well-rounded understanding of China
and a deeper understanding of China.
One more round of applaud for Professor Zhang.
Thank you, Professor Zhang.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组